Ace Books Records
Ace Books Records
1935-1962
Ace Books.
16 linear ft.
Manuscripts for periodicals published by Ace Books and photographs used for illustrations of Secrets, 1937.
148794
Biographical History
American publishing firm, specializing in popular literature.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ace Books Records consists of Manuscripts for periodicals published by Ace Books, including Confidential confessions, Daring romances, Love fiction, Revealing romances, and Secrets (1935-1962); and Photographs used for illustrations of Secrets, 1937.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by publication title, within that chronological.
Separated Material
The collection originally included published issues of a number of Ace periodicals, including Champion Sports, Confidential confessions, Detective dragnet, Flying aces, Love fiction, Red seal western, Secret agent-x, Sky birds, Western aces, and more. The collection also originally contained a number of Ace science fiction novels; these too have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Popular culture; Business and Industry; Ace Books.; Confidential confessions.; Daring romances.; Love fiction.; Revealing romances.; Secrets.; Confession stories -- Periodicals.; Love -- Fiction.; Love stories -- Periodicals.; Periodicals -- Publishing.; Popular literature -- Publishing.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Western stories -- Periodicals.; United States -- Popular culture.; Fiction.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Aaron Wynn, 1966-1968
Inventory
- Manuscripts
  - Confidential Confessions, 1960, Apr-Jul; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Confidential Confessions, 1960, Aug-Oct; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Confidential Confessions, 1960, Nov-Dec; 1961 Jan-Feb; 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Confidential Confessions, 1961, Mar-Jul; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Confidential Confessions, 1961, Aug-Oct; 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Confidential Confessions, 1961, Nov-Dec; 1962, Jan; 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Confidential Confessions, 1962, Feb-Mar; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Daring Romances, 1961, Jan-Mar; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Daring Romances, 1961, Mar-Jun; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Daring Romances, 1961, Jul-Oct; 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Daring Romances, 1961, Oct; 1962, Jan-Mar; 7 folders (Box 10)
  - Daring Romances, 1962, Nov-Dec; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Love Fiction, Oct 1935; Sep 1938; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Revealing Romances, 1959, Mar-Jun; 7 folders (Box 12)
  - Revealing Romances, 1959, Jun-Sep; 7 folders (Box 13)
  - Revealing Romances, 1959, Oct-Dec; 6 folders (Box 14)
  - Revealing Romances, 1960, Jan-Mar; 6 folders (Box 15)
  - Revealing Romances, 1961, Jan-Mar; 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Revealing Romances, 1961, Apr-Jun; 6 folders (Box 17)
  - Revealing Romances, 1961, Jun-Sep; 6 folders (Box 18)
  - Revealing Romances, 1961, Sep-Nov; 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Revealing Romances, 1961, Dec; 1962, Jan-Feb; 6 folders (Box 20)
  - Revealing Romances, 1962, Mar; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Secrets, Dec 1958; Jan 1959; 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Secrets, 1959, Feb-Apr; 6 folders (Box 22)
  - Secrets, 1959, May-Jul; 6 folders (Box 23)
  - Secrets, 1959, Aug-Oct; 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Secrets, 1959, Nov-Dec; 1960, Jan; 6 folders (Box 25)
  - Secrets, 1960, Feb-Apr; 6 folders (Box 26)
  - Secrets, 1960, May-Jul; 6 folders (Box 27)
  - Secrets, 1960, Aug-Oct; 6 folders (Box 28)
  - Secrets, 1960, Nov-Dec; 1961, Jan; 6 folders (Box 29)
  - Secrets, 1961, Feb-Apr; 6 folders (Box 30)
  - Secrets, 1961, May-Jul; 6 folders (Box 31)
  - Secrets, 1961, Aug-Oct; 6 folders (Box 32)
  - Secrets, 1961, Nov-Dec; 4 folders (Box 33)
- Photographs
  - Secrets, 1937, Jul-Aug; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Secrets, 1937, Sep-Dec; 4 folders (Box 33)
- Published material
  - Published issues of Ace periodicals, Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to and search on "Ace Books" to locate these items.
    Ace Sports
    Champion Sports
    Complete Love
    Confidential Confessions
    Daring Romances
    Detective Dragnet
    Flying Aces
    Love Fiction
    Red Seal Western
    Revealing Romances
    Secret Agent-X
    Secrets
    Sky Aces
    Sky Birds
    Ten Detective Aces
    Ten Story Detective
    Ten Story Love
    Twelve Sport Aces
    Variety Love
    Western Aces
    Western Trails